Guide to the Gertrude Lane Papers WAG.162
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Gertrude Lane Papers
Bulk, 1949-1953
1911-1960
WAG.162
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in two manuscript boxes
Gertrude Lane was secretary-treasurer and a founder of the Hotel and Club Employees Union, Local 6. This collection includes materials related to the NYC Hotel Trades Council and the Hotel, Restaurant and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 6, as well as personal and family papers and photographs. The collection also contains a small amount of materials created by Gertrude Lane's husband, Jay Rubin.
Lane, Gertrude
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by April Bloom (daughter of Gertrude Lane) in 2000. The accession number 2000.028 is associated with this collection.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Gertrude Lane was secretary-treasurer and a founder of the Hotel and Club Employees Union, Local 6 (now Hotel, Restaurant and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 6). Lane was married to labor organizer Jay Rubin, and died after an illness in 1953.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains correspondence, leaflets and photographs. Materials relate to the NYC Hotel Trades Council and the Hotel, Restaurant and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 6, as well as personal and family matters. The collection also contains a small amount of materials created by Gertrude Lane's husband, Jay Rubin.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic.
Bloom, April; Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union. Local 6 (Hotel, Restaurant and Club Employees Union) (New York, N.Y.).; Lane, Gertrude; New York Hotel Trades Council.; Rubin, Jay; Black-and-white photographs.; Correspondence.; Hotels |x Employees |z New York (State) |z New York.; Leaflets (printed works); Women in the labor movement |z United States.; Women labor union leaders |z United States.
- Clippings, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Family (April Rubin), 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Family (Ida and Shirley Levine), 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Financial, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Financial, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: General (1), 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: General (2), 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Illness, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: Local 6, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Hotel Trades Council: Leaflets (1), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Hotel Trades Council: Leaflets (2), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Hotel Trades Council: Leaflets (3), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Jay Rubin: Correspondence and Legal Documents, 1942-1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Local 6, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1911-1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photographs: Family, 1959-1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)